Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- William Santora Description: Early life in Jersey City, work at Emerson Radio N.Y., United Electrical Workers staff member helped organize Fed. Tel. and Tel., Westinghouse Elevator Co., N.J., influence of the left., Jul 24, 1980 (Cassette 218A-B)
- Sophie Saroff Description: Family background in Russia, 1905 Revolution; Rand School, ILGWU and Camp Unity; 1930s International Labor Defense., Dec 14, 1979 (Cassette 219A-E)
- Sophie Saroff Description: Recording of 80th b-day party, May 15, 1979 (Cd ohaloh0200144b1p1 / ohaloh0200144b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200145b1p3 / ohaloh0200145b1p4, Cd Access OH-02-155, OH-02-156, OH-02-157, OH-02-158, Cassette 144-145)
  Transcript Available, Box 2; Index available
- Daniel Boone Schirmer Description: National Students' League, CIO & students, Mar 18, 1981 (Cassette 221A-B)
- Charles Schwartz Description: Background in Fall River, 1950s-1960s; high school radicalization on; life and politics in Madison, late 1960s; down and out in California; return to New England, activities in Left, 1970s-1980s., Apr 21, 1984 (Cassette 222A-B)
- Chaym Schwartz Description: Activity as Yiddish poet in Yiddish Cultural circles, 1930s-present., Dec 29, 1981 (Cassette 223)
- Pete Seeger Description: Use of music as social protest; growing up in 1930s with folk music; Communist Party song book; war and prison sentence; sense of humor and curiosity; songs on Scottosboro and International Labor Defense., Feb 25, 1981 (Cassette 224A-B)
- Bernard Segal Description: Workman' Circle, Providence, R.I., 1920s-40s; ethnic socialist groups in Providence; Socialists and Communists., May 4, 1977 (Cassette 225)
- Bernard Segal, Jul 14, 1992 (Cd OH-02-153 and Oh-02-154, Cassette 412, Cd ohaloh0200143p1 / ohaloh0200143p2)
- Edith Segal Description: Music and dance and the Left in the 1930s., Feb 7, 1981 (Cassette 226, Cd ohaloh0200141p1 / ohaloh0200141p2, Cd Access OH-02-151)
- Irving Seid, Jun 4, 1976 (Cassette 227A, Box 1, Cd I. Seid 1-2)
  New York background; Depression and Unemployed Councils; McCarthyism.
  interview by Danny Czistrom.
- Tauhma Seid Description: Youth in Yorkville section of New York, 1920s; cafeteria workers unionism; Young Communist League; Communist Party, 1940s-50s., Jun 4, 1976 (Cassette 227B, Box 1, Cd T. Seid 1-2)
- Leo Seidlitz, Jul 20, 1983 (Cassette 229, 229.5, Cd Access OH-02-97, Box 1, Cassette 229 1-3, Cd ohaloh200097b2, Cd ohaloh200137b1p1 / ohaloh200137b1p2, Cd ohaloh200138b1p3 / ohaloh200138b1p4, Cd Seidlitz 1-3)
  Brooklyn College radical politics, mid-1930s; Trotskyism, late 1930s; Workers Party, 1940s, and later influence of Max Shachtman.
- Nina Serrano Description: Bohemian observations of middle-American Madison in 1950s; recruitment into Youth Labor League; activities in founding of the Peace Center; travel to Peace Festival, Moscow and to China; subsequent difficulty in school, Madison; maintaining contact with former Madison friends., Nov 16, 1983 (Cassette 230)
- Mark Sharron Description: Workers Party, Trotskyism, Workers' Party, Max Shachtman, 1930s-1950s., May 5, 1983 (Cassette 231A-B)
  Workers Party, Trotskyism, Workers' Party, Max Shachtman, 1930s-1950s.
- Mark Sharron, Aug 19, 1983 (Cd ohaloh0200096b1p1 / ohaloh0200096b1p2, Box 1, Cassette 232, Cassette Sharron 1-3, Cd Access OH-02-102, OH-02-103 and OH-02-104)
  Russian background; Brownsville childhood; City College of New York and Young Communist League; Trotskyism; European experiences; Workers Party and World War II.
- Mark Sharron, Nov 10, 1983 (Cd 0haloh0200098p1 / ohaloh0200098p2, Cassette 233, Cd Access OH-02-105 and OH-02-106, Box 1, Cassette 233 A-B, Cassette Sharron 4-5)
  Activity in the Trotskyist movement of the 1930s-40s; Trotskyism and international questions; character of the Workers Party.
- John Shenton Description: Socialist Party, Bridgeport, Conn., 1920-60., Jun 20, 1967 (Cassette Transcipt only)
- Moishe Shik, Dec 27, 1982 (Box 1, Cd Shik 1, Cassette 234, Cd ohaloh0200099p1 / ohaloh0200099p2)
- Anne Shore Description: Communist Party; United office and Professional Workers of America (UOPWA); picketing of the Nazi ship Bremen; Detroit, 1940s; Civil Rights Congress and Progressive Party, Los Angeles, late 1940s-early 1950s; effects of McCarthy period; work for 1199 (Hospital Workers), 1960s., May 31, 1982 - Jun 15, 1982 (Cassette 235A-H)
- Meyer Shticker, undated (Cassette 405)
- Elias Shulman, Oct 19, 1982 (Cassette 300, Box 1, Cd Shulman 1)
  Interview by Paul Buhle
- Leo Seidlitz, Aug 22 1983 (Cassette 353)
- Madeline Simon, Nov 5, 2002
  Transcript available, Box 2 Release form
- Robert J. Silverstein & Howard Meyers Description: International Labor Defense, National Lawyers Guild 1930s-40s, Jun 22, 1982 (Cassette 236A-B)
- Fanny S. Simon, Feb 12, 1982 (Box 1, Cd Trager 1-2, Cd Simon 1-2, Cd ohaloh020251b1p1, ohaloh020251b1p2, Cd ohaloh020252b1p3, Cd Access OH-02-274, OH-02-275, Cassette 237A-B)
  Socialist Party 1930s.
- Donald Slaiman, Dec 16, 1994 (Cassette 341)
- Jessie Taft Smith Description: Family background in Norwalk, Connecticut, 1910s-1920s; Young Communist League, laundry workers' union, social and political life, 1930s., Nov 19, 1981 (Cassette 238A-B)
- Mar 31, 1983 (Cassette 239)
- Socialist Labor Party Description: Socialist Labor Party "South Slavonian" language federation, 1920s-50s, Detroit and Cleveland., Mar 17, 1983 (Cassette 240A-D)
- Southern Negro Youth Congres, Feb 6, 1984 (Cd ohaloh0200108b1p1 / ohaloh0200108b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200109b1p3 / ohaloh0200109b1p4, Cassette 241, Box 1, Cd SNYC 1-2, Cassette 241 1-2)
  Forum on its history, with one-time SNYC activists Henry Winston, James Jackson, Grace Tillman Bassett, Esther Jackson, and Dorothy Burnham.
- Anton Srok, Jul 26, 1983 (Cd ohaloh0200100b1p1 / ohaloh0200100b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200101b1p3, Cassette 242, Box 1, Cd Srok 1-2, Cassette 242 A-B)
  Activities in Milwaukee Croatian Fraternal Union, 1930s-present; labor activities in Milwaukee during 1930s; theatrical activities of interviewee, a prominent amateur Croatian-American actor in Milwaukee.
- Anna Srunsky-Walling, Jul 17, 1960 (Cassette 292A-C)
- Morton Stavis Description: Social Security Administration, unionism and civil rights, working with Senator Wagner; War Labor Board, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Carl and Anne Braden; civil rights cases: McSurley Case 1967, Philippines Case 1986., Jan 20, 1990 - Feb 7, 1991 (Cassette 314A-D)
- Sid Sterin & Eugene Dennis Description: Speech of Sid Stein in debate with Eugene Dennis at CPUSA Executive Committee, Dec 1957 (Cassette 325)
- Charlotte Stern Description: no description currently available., May 7, 1979 (Cassette 330A-B)
- Sholem Stern, Sep 18, 1978 (Cassette 243, Box 1, Cd Stern 1, Cd ohaloh0200102p1 / ohaloh0200102p2)
  Radical Yiddish writer and poet, Montreal and New York, 1920s-30s.
- Sholem Stern, undated (Cassette 406)
- Isidor Steuzert, Oct 27, 1982 (Box 1, Cassette Steuzert 1, Cassette 244, Cd ohaloh0200103p1)
  The Jewish Socialist Federation, American Communism, the Lovestoneites.
- Chambers Stewart, Jun 22, 1983 (Cassette 382)
- Chaim Suller, Jan 20, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Suller 1, Cd ohaloh0200104p1 / ohaloh0200104p2, Cassette 245)
  Background in Jewish progressive movement; problems of the Morgen Freiheit today.
- Arne Swabeck Description: Large collections of interviews taken in the 1970s, Apr 7, 1975 - Apr 11, 1975 (Cassette 246A-WW)
- Arne Swabeck, Oct 23, 1982 (Cd ohaloh200105b1p1 / ohaloh200105b1p2, Cd ohaloh200106b1p3 / ohaloh200106bap4, Cassette 246, Box 1, Cd Swabeck 1-2, Cassette 246 A-B)
  Scandinavian Socialist Federation and press.
- A.O Syrstad, Jan 5, 1978 (Cd ohaloh0200107p1, Box 1, Cd Syrstad 1, Cassette 247)
  Workers Party, Independent Socialist League, Seattle, Washington, 1940s-1950s.
  Interview by Allen Thompson.
- Loretta Szeliga, Dec 8, 1981 (Carton 354)
- Elliot Sullivan Memorial Service, undated
- Anna Taffler Description: Unemployed Council Brooklyn 1930-1934, Jan 5, 1978 (Cassette 248A-B)
- Stephen Tendler, Oct 5, 1984 (Cassette 411)
- Norman Thomas Description: Reminiscences, 1960 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Norman Thomas Description: Recollections of Jasper McLevy, Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, Conn., 1933-1957., Nov 17, 1966 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Norman Thomas: 1932 Campaign, 50th anniversary Description: Various speakers including Ruth Senior, Mickey Most, Herb Wolfe, John Herling, Noah Walter, Michael Harrington; recollections of Thomas' first presidential campaign and his overall career and influence., Nov 19, 1982 - Nov 20, 1982 (Cassette 251A-F)
  Transcript availalbe, Box 2 and index available
- Bessie Thomashow Description: Workmen's Circle, 1930s, undated (Cassette 253)
- Fred Thompson, Jul 26, 1983 (Cassette 254, Cd ohaloh0200116b1p1 / ohaloh0200116b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200117b1p3, Cd ohaloh0200118p1 / ohaloh0200118p2, Box 1, Cd 1-2, Cassette 254 A-B)
  Nature of language federations attached to Industrial Workers of the World; prominent immigrant figures in IWW; eclipse of language federations and ethnic press in IWW.
- Fred Thompson, Apr 1983 (Box 1, Cd Thompson 3-4, Cassette 255)
- Alan Thomson, Feb 11, 1993 (Cassette 327A-B)
- Ahrne Thorne, Jan 22, 1983 (Cassette 256A-B, Box 1, Cd Thorne 1-2)
  tape#: 1 U2CC
  Polish background; education of an anarchist; Yiddish anarchism in the US since the 1920s; Yiddish anarchism and Zionism; Rudolf Rocker.
- Ahrne Thorne, undated (Cassette 407)
- Frank Trager, undated (Box 1, Cd Trager 1-2, Cd Access OH-02-276, OH-02-277, Cassette 238, Cd ohaloh020253b1p1, ohaloh020253b1p2)
- Haunani-Kay Trask, undated (Cassette 303A-B)
- Esther Travaglio, Oct 30, 1982 (Cassette 257, Box 1, Cassette 257 A-B, Cd ohaloh200110b1p1 / ohaloh200110b1p2, Cd ohaloh200111b1p3, Cassette Travaglio 1-2)
  Activity of "Gene" Travaglio, anarchist activist and job-printer in Seattle and in California; background and activities of Esther Hartz Travaglio.
- Jerry Trauber, Nov 4, 1979 (Cassette 408)
- Uhro Tuuomien, Nov 5, 1983 (Box 1, Cassette 258, Cd ohaloh200112p1 / ohaloh200112p2, Cd Tuuominen 1)
  Activity of "younger" generation of Finnish-American radicals in Midwest and California; tenacity and decline of Finnish-American activity in Bay Area; effort of Communist and non-Communist Finnish-Americans to engage in common functions.
- Jean Tussey, Oct 24, 1978 - Oct 25, 1978, Mar 20, 1979 (Cassette 259, Cd ohaloh0200113b1p1 / ohaloh0200113b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200114b1p3 / ohaloh0200114b1p4, Cd ohaloh0200115b1p5 / ohaloh0200115b1p6, Box 1, Cassette 259 A-C, Cd Tussey 1-4)
  Steel Workers Organizing Committee, Socialist Party, and Socialist Workers Party in New Jersey and Southern California, 1930s-early 1940s.
- Gus Tyler, Oct 29, 1973 (Cd Access OH-02 278, OH-02-279, Cd 339, Cd ohaloh020254b1p1, ohaloh020254b1p2, ohaloh020255b1p3)
- Session of 1983 New York State Labor History Association meeting Description:Presentation by Roy Rosenzweig, followed by panel discussion with Saul Parker, John Gates, Rose Schuyler, Brendan Sexton., Apr 30, 1983 (Cassette 261A-B)
- Unidentified Ukrainian Poet, Mar 21, 1979 (Cassette 390)
- Willard Uphaus and Ruth MacLenna Description: Religion-political activity, friendship with Claude Williams, c. 1930s., Jul 20, 1983 (Cassette 262A-B)
- Vittorio Vidali Description: Italian Language Federation, American Communist movement, 1920s; translated from his autobiography., Aug 6, 1981 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Abraham Vishnu & Getzel Becker, Oct 25, 1978 (Cassette 264, Box 1, Cd Vishnu & Becker 1, Cd ohaloh200119b1p1 / ohaloh200119b1p2, Cassette 264 A-B)
  Radicalism and culture in New York and Miami Beach; anti-semitism in radical movements of Poland; life for Jewish workers in pre-revolutionary Cuba; importance of Yiddish culture for political movements, 1920s-1950s.
- Frank Wallin Description: Editorial activities for Tyomies and Industrilistii, Finnish-American IWW newspaper; life of a Finnish-American radical newspaperman, 1940s-1970s., Jul 31, 1983 (Box 2)
- Hershel Walker, undated (Cassette 356-357)
- Jacob Waisbord, Jun 28, 1993 (Cassette 340A-B)
- Albert Warner, May 3, 1980 (Cassette 305A-B)
- Susan Warren Description: Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy; Jefferson School of Social Science, 1950s., Apr 17, 1966 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Arthur Waskow Description: Students for a Democratic Society, Apr 2, 1970 (Cassette no tape)
- Stan Weir Description: C.L.R. James and Johnson-Forest Tendency, Workers Party, Oct 22, 1982 (Cassette 269A-M)
- Sam Weiss Description: Role of the Freie Arbeter Shtimme (Free Voice of Labor) in the labor movement of the 1920s-1930s; anarchists within Arbeter Ring., Apr 8, 1980 (Cassette 271)
- Louis Weiss, Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 384A-B)
- Saul Wellman Description: Communists & United Auto Workers during WWII, Hitler-Stalin pact, cold war and Left, Aug 24, 1972 (Cassette Index Only)
  No tape
- Myra Tanner Weiss Description: Unemployed movement and Trotskyist movement; anti-fascist demonstrations; experiences as Socialist Workers Party candidate; c. 1920s-1950s., 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-152, Cassette 270, Cd ohaloh0200142p1 / ohaloh0200142p2)
- Saul Wellman: 65th birthday dinner, 1980 (Box 1, Cd Wellman dinner 1-3, Cassette 273 A-B, Cassette 273, Cd ohaloh200122b1p1 / ohaloh200122b1p2, Cd ohaloh200123b1p3 / ohaloh200123b1p4)
- Ed Wiese Description: Westinghouse Elevator Plant, Jersey City; President, Local 456; U.E., 1981 (Cassette 274A-B)
- Yvette West Description: youth in IWW, mid-1930s; father (Yiddish critic B. Rivkin), his literary career., Jan 19, 1983 (Cassette 275A-B, Cd OH-02-275A side A / OH-02-275A side B / OH-02-275B side A)
- Jim Williams Description: Students for a Democratic society 1960s, Apr 2, 1970 (Cassette 276)
- Paul W. Williams Description: Prosecution of International Workers' Order 1950s, May 11, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Tim Wohlforth Description: Bridgeport, Connecticut; Socialism and Trotskyism; c. 1930s- 1950s., Aug 29, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Alice Dodge Wolfson Description: League for Industrial Democracy, Office Workers Union, New England CIO and Socialist Party, 1930s., Apr 1, 1982 (Cassette 279)
- Workers Party/Standing Fast Conference Description: Commemorating the opening of the Max Shachtman Papers at the Tamiment Library; panel presentations on 1) the character and activities of the Workers Party, 1940-49 2) Harvey Swados' novel Standing Fast, based on the WP, and 3) three magazines with roots in the WP, Politics, Dissent, and New Politics. Speakers include Herman Benson, Ricky Flanders, Albert Glotzer, Julius Jacobson, Irving Sanes, Morton Clurman, Paul Cowan, Lewis Coser, Robert Cummings, Phyllis Jacobson., May 6, 1983 - May 7, 1983 (Cassette 280A-H)
- Frederick Wright Description: Work as a clip- joint musician and freelance cartoonist for NMU; Cold War and shift to UE News; c. 1920s-1940s., Jun 20, 1984 (Cassette 281)
- Fanny Yellin, Apr 16, 1980 (Box 1, Cassette 282, Cd Yellin 1)
  Anarchist circle in Philadelphia, 1910s; personality and ideas of Rudolf Rocker; role of the Rocker Circle, Los Angeles, in publishing Rocker's work and facilitating his speaking tours.
- Karl Yoneda, Jan 7, 1983 (Cassette 283, Box 1, Cd Yoneda 1)
  Japanese-American Communist movement in the 1920s-30s; Japanese-language press, 1920s and early 1930s; sectarian errors; cultural events; role in labor movement and opposition to internment camps; Popular Front in Japanese-American Left; Asian-American labor, 1980s.
- Vincent Young Description: Congress of Radical Equality, Brooklyn; Downstate Medical Center, New York World's Fair demonstrations; CORE conventions and campaigns; c. 1940s-1960s., Aug 4, 1983 (Cassette 244-246, Cd ohaloh020244b1p1 / ohaloh020244b1p2, Cd ohaloh020245b1p3 /ohaloh020245b1p3, Cd ohaloh020246n1p5 / ohaloh020246n1p6, Cd Access OH-02-267, OH-02-268, OH-02-269)
  No Access Cassette 284C / Master only
- Mary Zackheim, Oct 24, 1978 (Cd ohaloh200124b1p1 / ohaloh200124b1p2, Cd ohaloh200125b1p3 / ohaloh200125b1p4, Box 1, Cassette 285 1-2, Cd Mary Zackheim 1-2, Cassette 285)
- Meyer Zackheim Description: New York Left in 1910s-20s; problems of Jewish progressive movement in Miami Beach, 1970s., Oct 24, 1978 (Box 1, Cd Meyer Zackheim 1, Cassette 286.5, Cd ohaloh200128p1)
- Zackheim, Glassmans, Klieger, Rosenfeld (Group #III), Oct 24, 1978 (Cd ohaloh200126b1p1 / ohaloh200126b1p2, Cd ohaloh200127b1p3 / ohaloh200127b1p4, Box 1, Cassette 286 A-B, Cassette 286)
  New York Progressive Yiddish activity in 1920s-40s; immigration and trade union; role of progressive movement in Miami Beach Jewish community, 1970s.
- Meyer Zackheim, Archie Rothenberg & Rose Lipshitz, Oct 24, 1978 (Cassette 287.5, Cd ohaloh200131p1 / ohaloh200131p2, Box 1, Cd Zackheim, Rothenberg & Lipshitz 1)
  Problems of immigrant women (Rose Lipshitz) in America of 1920s and appeal of the Left; political activities of Jewish Left in 1920s-30s (Rothenberg); YKUF reading circles.
- Meyer Zackheim, Ed Weiss, Silvers (group #I ), Oct 24, 1978 (Box 1, Cassette 287, Cd Zackheim, Weiss & Silvers 1-2, Cd ohaloh0200129b1p1 / ohaloh0200129b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200130b1p3 / ohaloh0200130b1p3)
- Joseph Zawadowski, Jul 28, 1983 (Cassette 288, Cd ohaloh200132b1p1 / ohaloh200132b1p2, Cd ohaloh200133b1p3 / ohaloh200133b1p4, Box 1, Cassette 288 1-2, Cd Zadowski 1-2)
  Polish-American Left in Chicago from time of his father (1920s) to present; Spanish Civil War experiences; current activities of Chicago Left.
- Steve Zeluck, Dec 15, 1982 (Cassette 289, Box 1, Cd ohaloh200134p1 / ohaloh200134p2, Cd Zeluck 1)
  Johnson-Forest Tendency; Trotskyist movement, Philadephia and Chicago; reflections on C.L.R. James.
- Steve Zeluck, undated (Cassette 410)
- Charles Zimmerman, Oct 31, 1974 (Cassette 290, Cd ohaloh020085b1p1 / ohaloh020085b1p2, Cd ohaloh020086b1p3 / ohaloh020086b1p4, Cd Access OH-02-089 / OH-02-90, Box 1, Cassette 290 A-B, Cd Zimmerman 1-2)
  International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, struggle between left and right, 1910s-20s.
  Interview by David Gurowsky.
- Celia Lewis Zitron Description: New York Teachers Union, 1940s, May 8, 1976